<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-27T22:21:50-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Weiwei Hsu</title><subtitle>Minimal Jekyll theme for storytellers</subtitle><author><name>Weiwei</name><email>wei@weiweihsu.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Collective creative freedom | #18</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-27/weeknotes-18" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Collective creative freedom | #18" /><published>2019-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-27/weeknotes-18</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-27/weeknotes-18">&lt;p&gt;In my weeknotes &lt;a href=&quot;http://weiweihsu.com/2018-11-10/weeknote-9&quot;&gt;#9&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote about the idea creative freedom:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This idea of gaining creative freedom, or research freedom, is perhaps something that I find many different communities strive for (the new indie vc movement, digital nomads, patreon creators, kickstarter creators, indie hackers, to name a few.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The question I’ve been thinking about this week, in relation to creative freedom, is whether there should be a school that helps you to gain creative freedom. Job security is no longer the only goal people have for their careers. However, it is still very hard for people to wrap their head around, and be brave enough to get started with gaining creative freedom (especially those who live in an environment that culturally encourages to climb the corporate ladder, or stick with a ‘safe job’.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I believe that Secret Project Taiwan was a step toward that direction, but currently I don’t know how I could be taking it another step furthur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 months later, I think I now have a better sense of how to begin to own creative freedom, collectively. Hopefully, I will have more to share soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite a lot of things happened this week..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since graduation, I have been thinking a lot about what I would like to work on, and how I can get there. A few months have gone by now, and I think I’ve realized that I need a balance between exploring and experimenting with tools creation, but at the same time, making it available and accessible to others. At the same time, I’ve been searching for places where I can explore the intersection of computing and architecture/urbanism. I think I have found a group of people that does precisely these, and it feels like discovering earthlings when you think you are the only one residing on Mars..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a publication date for the first paper that I’ve co-authored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to school to pick up my student excellence in leadership awards, and reading about why I was nominated and awarded with the awards feels like getting a flashback of everything that happened during college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most importantly, I feel a lot clearer about what I want to do and how I can get there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">In my weeknotes #9, I wrote about the idea creative freedom:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Break, Home, Back | #17</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-13/weeknotes-17" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Break, Home, Back | #17" /><published>2019-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-13/weeknotes-17</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-13/weeknotes-17">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a month since I last synced weeknotes to the website. I tried out writing weeknotes in Apple Notes for the last month and I think I still prefer writing it in Atom and pushing it to the world of connected bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a wonderful break. I was able to spend a ton of time at home, catch up with friends that I get to see once every 2-4 years, and reflect on the past few months as well as the past 4 four years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some feelings:
It’s weird to be back and see how the place I grew up in feels unfamiliar because of how technology is now weaved into the city. It’s exciting to see how people that I’ve crossed paths with before are all working toward their own goals. It’s motivating to see how companies here work, collaborate, and experiment to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
I’m now at the airport. It’s been a while since I last spent this many weeks at home. And when home finally feels normal again, it’s time to leave. It feels weird to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having taken a break, where I was able to truly get bored, it’s time to get serious this year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">It’s been a month since I last synced weeknotes to the website. I tried out writing weeknotes in Apple Notes for the last month and I think I still prefer writing it in Atom and pushing it to the world of connected bits.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book, Communication | #16</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-06/weeknotes-16" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book, Communication | #16" /><published>2019-01-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-06/weeknotes-16</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-06/weeknotes-16">&lt;p&gt;Spent the first day of 2019 finishing Kaifu Lee’s “AI Superpower”. It’s been a while since I’ve started and finished a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to read the book in Chinese because I’ve realized that it’s hard for me to have a conversation about anything technology related in Chinese, that’s because I learned to talk about design and technology in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned quite a bit from reading the book, and seeing how he positioned the book in different countries. The book also showed me a way to explain some of the dangers and solutions to those who think technology has near-zero negative impact.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">Spent the first day of 2019 finishing Kaifu Lee’s “AI Superpower”. It’s been a while since I’ve started and finished a book.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Things in 2018 | #15</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-30/weeknotes-15" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Things in 2018 | #15" /><published>2018-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-30/weeknotes-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-30/weeknotes-15">&lt;p&gt;I wanted to document everything I’ve done and have not done this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why I’ve decided to do this is because I’ve graduate from college, and life/what I’ve done is entirely up to me (although that is true to school too.) This will probably be the 10000th times you’ve seen someone doing this, but this will be the first time for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got very sick in January because of over-working in the previous semester&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got to invite the designer I respect the most to speak at CCA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got to meet someone I first met on Twitter in person&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I promised myself to not slack off on thesis and I didn’t&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduated from CCA with distinction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Co-won a grant to work on a housing project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got the highest grade for thesis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thesis zine was exhibited in New York&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrote a paper with my favorite teacher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talked to an English-speaking energy worker for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Traveled to New York for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Took on multiple contract work at once&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explored and researched different business models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launched and shipped a Kickstarter project for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had my first holiday break as an ‘adult’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reunited with more than half of my high school classmates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learned to do basic modeling in Rhino&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coded my website&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made an analog version of my portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visited a Chinese Tech company&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started reading books in Chinese again&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confronted the reality of fighting for creative and research freedom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overall, I was very confused with what I want to do, how I could fit in in the design world, and if I should try and fit in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–
It is now one hour away from 2019. Unlike some people, I don’t feel like 2018 is a year that I cannot top, but it also wasn’t a bad year. I feel like, one bad habit I got rid of this year was how lazy I get after thinking through how a project can play out (I used to think that if a project can happen, then I don’t really need to realize it..)
One thing I aiming to get better at next year, is to execute a ton more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">I wanted to document everything I’ve done and have not done this year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Payment systems, Alternative Business Models| #14</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-23/weeknotes-14" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Payment systems, Alternative Business Models| #14" /><published>2018-12-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-23/weeknotes-14</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-23/weeknotes-14">&lt;p&gt;This time back, I’ve been ordering customized prints and cards for friend’s companies and myself. That process (not really an experience) is an entirely different one than in America. In America, most people have built a website that covers the entire process so that they don’t have to interface with you. Here in China, you would view their store to get the gist of what you would receive, but the negotiation and file-checking etc are all through a chat. I gotta say, I prefer the latter, even though there are rarely any pretty visual design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a version of the custom brass stamp I’m ordering. You can switch out the characters because there’s a removable stopper that’s magnetically attached to the stamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/letter stamp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;custom-made stamp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">This time back, I’ve been ordering customized prints and cards for friend’s companies and myself. That process (not really an experience) is an entirely different one than in America. In America, most people have built a website that covers the entire process so that they don’t have to interface with you. Here in China, you would view their store to get the gist of what you would receive, but the negotiation and file-checking etc are all through a chat. I gotta say, I prefer the latter, even though there are rarely any pretty visual design.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Payment systems, Alternative Business Models| #13</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-16/weeknotes-13" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Payment systems, Alternative Business Models| #13" /><published>2018-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-16/weeknotes-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-16/weeknotes-13">&lt;p&gt;Skipped a week of weeknotes because I was traveling and getting distracted by being home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I’m using Alipay and WeChat Pay and it’s so fascinating to participate in this ecosystem. There hasn’t been a store/place that doesn’t accept one of those payment. In fact, most places don’t accept credit cards and only accept Alipay or WeChat Pay (this is due to the face that shops need to pay a deposit to rent the device to accept payment, and accepting multiple forms of payments means paying for lots of deposit $$$)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a version of Square in China, the main difference here is that there’s a camera for scanning QR code. Another difference is that, every store I’ve been to almost always has a different payment machine/device, probably because each comes with different features and are sold at a different price point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/paymentsh.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;payment device in Shanghai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently watched Connie Chan’s video on &lt;a href=&quot;https://weiweihsu.typeform.com/to/PuycXI&quot;&gt;alternative business models in China&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s pretty inspiring to see all of those business models all-at-once. In America, and most of the world, there exist three different models: subscription-based, ad-based (hence attention-based), and/or a mix of both. In China, there are ebook apps where you only need to pay to unlock the ending, or you pay by the # of characters you read, there are streaming services where you pay only after watching the first five minutes of the movie, or you pay by tipping the authors/creators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great motivation for pursuing alternative business models when creating digital and analog products.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">Skipped a week of weeknotes because I was traveling and getting distracted by being home.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflection | #12</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-01/weeknote-12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflection | #12" /><published>2018-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-01/weeknote-12</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-01/weeknote-12">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve been looking back at the think wrong chart, and thinking about how I’m falling into the trap of going for the safe route. To be honest, ever since graduation, societal pressure around getting a job has been pulling me away from all the ambitions I had when I was in freshman and sophomore year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have learned a lot in the past few months, especially around the importance of aligning goals, and how to frame a proposal. I think it is fair to say that I’m now more motivated to work on what I believe in.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">Recently, I’ve been looking back at the think wrong chart, and thinking about how I’m falling into the trap of going for the safe route. To be honest, ever since graduation, societal pressure around getting a job has been pulling me away from all the ambitions I had when I was in freshman and sophomore year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conversations, Income Sharing Agreements | #11</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-25/weeknote-11" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=" Conversations, Income Sharing Agreements | #11" /><published>2018-11-25T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-11-25/weeknote-11</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-25/weeknote-11">&lt;p&gt;📓&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Triggered by some recent conversations, I’ve been spending a good portion of this week reflecting upon my post-graduation life. I think I’m getting a much better sense of what I want to learn and how I want to contribute. It is often surprising how long it takes to articulate thoughts, and feelings. For thesis, I probably struggled with what I was trying to do for the entire first semester. It wasn’t until the second semester, or rather, the last month, and I had a good sense of what I was investigating. Which makes me wonder if, the time spent on trying to articulate an investigation, is porprotional to the meaningfulness of the investigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone told me to cease doubting myself and just jump and do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–
🎓&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been listening to a few podcasts about income sharing agreements. I’m suprised to learn that Yale University was the first university to experiment with it, about 10 years ago, and failed miserably. It’s interesting how there has been an increase in startups that are using this model. Perhaps at some point, this will pressure colleges of different to experiment with it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">📓</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LA, Scooters | #10</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-18/weeknote-10" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LA, Scooters | #10" /><published>2018-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-11-18/weeknote-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-18/weeknote-10">&lt;p&gt;–
🎤&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still need to get better at pitching and proposing. It doesn’t feel like I can effectively highlight the key points I want to communicate, perhaps because I’m not experienced enough, or, perhaps I just need to prepr and practice more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–
🏞&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been one of the most stressful and relaxing week of the year, but I’m pretty sure there are a few more of these weeks coming before the end of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spending the second half of the week in LA to take a break. I’m really liking this style of working hard and playing hard. It is so refreshing and inspiring to step out of my life, and to breathe and be exposed to other urban areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very grateful for having the opportunity to do take a break like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/natureinla.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Nature in LA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–
🛴&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many scooters and bikes in Santa Monica, it is so much fun to inspect all scooter generations on one street. I must say, visual design can really help to differentiate one brand from another. Out of all the scooters I’ve seen in NorCal and SoCal, I definitely like JUMP and Lyft’s scooters the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also fascinating how everyone I know is now fluent in the scooter language, regardless of whether they love or hate the them. I suppose this is the difference when your products are in real life, versus being digital and not really discoverable unless with intentional marketing. I wonder if meaningful products can be just as discoverable as scooters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/scooters.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;JUMP and Lyft scooters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JUMP’s branding is pretty slick in my opinion. The way they wrap their logo around the scooter and the bike is great. I also like how their logo on the scooter is retroreflective. It’s kind of a bummer to me that they’ve been acquired by Uber. I really wish that they are an independent startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jumpmicro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;JUMP scooter and bike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">– 🎤</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creative freedom, School, Micromobility | #9</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-10/weeknote-9" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creative freedom, School, Micromobility | #9" /><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-11-10/weeknote-9</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-10/weeknote-9">&lt;p&gt;Been listening to quite a few podcasts about Patreon and Kickstarter lately. This idea of gaining creative freedom, or research freedom, is perhaps something that I find many different communities strive for (the new indie vc movement, digital nomads, patreon creators, kickstarter creators, indie hackers, to name a few.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very excited to see where all of these movements lead to, and genuinely hope that I will be able to contribute to it. Perhaps, launching BBCube is the first step toward that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the Secret Project Taiwan members are in SF this fall as exchange students. Meeting with them has reminded me of the sptw sessions that I ran in the summer of 2015 and 2016. To a very large extent, that’s still the project that I’m the most proud of, and would like to continue working on at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question I’ve been thinking about this week, in relation to creative freedom, is whether there should be a school that helps you to gain creative freedom. Job security is no longer the only goal people have for their careers. However, it is still very hard for people to wrap their head around, and be brave enough to get started with gaining creative freedom (especially those who live in an environment that culturally encourages to climb the corporate ladder, or stick with a ‘safe job’.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most schools today ride on their existing reputation and cannot promise job security. What I like about &lt;a href=&quot;https://lambdaschool.com&quot;&gt;Lambda School&lt;/a&gt;’s model is that they’ve structured their business model around motivating themselves to help students secure a job. What I wish exists, in addition to what Lambda School is doing, is perhaps a school or program that teaches people courage and assists people in launching their indie products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that Secret Project Taiwan was a step toward that direction, but currently I don’t know how I could be taking it another step furthur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;600vh&quot; height=&quot;360vh&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PajTIWf_fqI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that scooters are back in SF, I find myself not liking it as much as I thought I would. It is still very convinient to have scooters as a transportation option, but I’ve been using JUMP bikes significantly more. JUMP bikes are cheaper than scooters (per minute), you kind of get an exercise out of it, and it is fun to zip around the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing some desktop research on different ebikes brand, as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/speculatvglitch/status/1056778492447084544&quot;&gt;renting and charging as a service&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uma.com&quot;&gt;Uma&lt;/a&gt; offers. It is so fascinating how very few people/organizations saw micromobility coming, yet it is changing how lower and middle social class people can commute. I remember hearing someone complaining about how “we were promised flying cars and we got 140 words (Twitter)”, but I personally think the future always play out this way, and there’s nothing bad about this. A society advances not necessarily because of a new invention, but because of &lt;em&gt;a new way to organize existing things&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">Been listening to quite a few podcasts about Patreon and Kickstarter lately. This idea of gaining creative freedom, or research freedom, is perhaps something that I find many different communities strive for (the new indie vc movement, digital nomads, patreon creators, kickstarter creators, indie hackers, to name a few.)</summary></entry></feed>