<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-23T22:24:22-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Weiwei Hsu</title><subtitle>Minimal Jekyll theme for storytellers</subtitle><author><name>Weiwei</name><email>wei@weiweihsu.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">LA, Scooters | #10</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-18/weeknote-10" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=" LA, Scooters | #10" /><published>2018-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-11-18/weeknote-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-18/weeknote-10">&lt;p&gt;–
🎤&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still need to get better at pitching and proposing. It doesn’t feel like I can effectively highlight the key points I want to convey, perhaps because I’m not as experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–
🏞&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been one of the most stressful and relaxing week of the year, but I’m pretty sure there are a few more of these weeks coming before the end of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spending the second half of the week in LA to take a break. I’m really liking this style of working hard and playing hard. It is so refreshing and inspiring to step out of my life, and to breathe and be exposed to other urban areas. Very grateful for having the opportunity to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/natureinla.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Nature in LA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–
🛴&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many scooters and bikes in Santa Monica, it is so much fun to inspect all scooter generations on one street. I must say, visual design can really help to differentiate one brand from another. Out of all the scooters I’ve seen in NorCal and SoCal, I definitely like JUMP and Lyft’s scooters the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also fascinating how everyone I know is now fluent in the scooter language, regardless of whether they love or hate the them. I suppose this is the difference when your products are in real life, versus being digital and not really discoverable unless with intentional marketing. I wonder if meaningful products can be just as discoverable as scooters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/scooters.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;JUMP and Lyft scooters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JUMP’s branding is pretty slick in my opinion. The way they wrap their logo around the scooter and the bike is great. I also like how their logo on the scooter is retroreflective. It’s kind of a bummer to me that they’ve been acquired by Uber. I really wish that they are an independent startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jumpmicro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;JUMP scooter and bike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">– 🎤</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creative freedom, School, Micromobility | #9</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-10/weeknote-9" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creative freedom, School, Micromobility | #9" /><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-11-10/weeknote-9</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-10/weeknote-9">&lt;p&gt;Been listening to quite a few podcasts about Patreon and Kickstarter lately. This idea of gaining creative freedom, or research freedom, is perhaps something that I find many different communities strive for (the new indie vc movement, digital nomads, patreon creators, kickstarter creators, indie hackers, to name a few.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very excited to see where all of these movements lead to, and genuinely hope that I will be able to contribute to it. Perhaps, launching BBCube is the first step toward that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the Secret Project Taiwan members are in SF this fall as exchange stduents. Meeting with them has reminded me of the sptw sessions that I ran in the summer of 2015 and 2016. To a very large extent, that’s still the project that I’m the most proud of, and would like to continue working on that at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question I’ve been thinking about this week, in relation to creative freedom, is whether there should be a school that helps you to gain creative freedom. Job security is no longer the only goal people have for their careers. However, it is still very hard for people to wrap their head around, and be brave enough to get started with gaining creative freedom (especially those who live in an environment that culturally encourages to climb the corporate ladder, or stick with a ‘safe job’.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most schools today ride on their existing reputation and cannot promise job security. What I like about &lt;a href=&quot;https://lambdaschool.com&quot;&gt;Lambda School&lt;/a&gt;’s model is that they’ve structured their business model around motivating themselves to help students secure a job. What I wish exists, in addition to what Lambda School is doing, is perhaps a school or program that teaches people courage and assists people in launching their indie products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that Secret Project Taiwan is a step toward that direction, but currently I don’t know how I could be taking it another step furthur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;600vh&quot; height=&quot;360vh&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PajTIWf_fqI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that scooters are back in SF, I find myself not liking it as much as I thought I would. It is still very convinient to have scooters as a transportation option, but I’ve been using JUMP bikes significantly more. JUMP bikes are cheaper than scooters (per minute), you kind of get an exercise out of it, and it is fun to zip around the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing some desktop research on different ebikes brand, as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/speculatvglitch/status/1056778492447084544&quot;&gt;renting and charging as a service&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uma.com&quot;&gt;Uma&lt;/a&gt; offers. It is so fascinating how very few people/organizations saw micromobility coming, yet it is changing how lower and middle social class people can commute. I remember hearing someone complaining about how “we were promised flying cars and we got 140 words (Twitter)”, but I personally think the future always play out this way, and there’s nothing bad about this. A society advances not necessarily because of a new invention, but because of &lt;em&gt;a new way to organize existing things&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">Been listening to quite a few podcasts about Patreon and Kickstarter lately. This idea of gaining creative freedom, or research freedom, is perhaps something that I find many different communities strive for (the new indie vc movement, digital nomads, patreon creators, kickstarter creators, indie hackers, to name a few.)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Podcasts, Goal | #8</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-04/weeknote-8" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Podcasts, Goal | #8" /><published>2018-11-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-11-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-11-04/weeknote-8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-11-04/weeknote-8">&lt;p&gt;This week, I’ve finally abandoned Apple Podcasts and switched to Breaker Podcasts. I’v had the Breaker app for a few months now but was never compelled to actually start using it. It wasn’t until a podcast I was listening to had half of their season missing on Apple Podcasts, that I decided to switch to Breaker, and I will probably never look back. Different from the Apple Podcasts, I love the fact that you can adjust playing speed and make it specific to each podcast. It’s also helpful to see how many podcasts I’ve listened to; I’ve never gotten a sense on how many podcasts I’ve completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When speaking to a consultancy earlier in the week, I’ve realized what I’m truly interested in: In senior year, I became borderline obssessed with long-term technology research, and spoke with roughly 30 technology researchers. At the same time, I’m always interested in poetic products and putting things in the world. So what does it look like if I merge the two? My current conclusion is that, I want to apply long-term thinking to the creation of poetic and meaningful products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably because of the podcasts I’m listening to, I’ve been thinking a lot about doing things that don’t scale. I fundamentally believe in this when starting out (anything). This has always been how I started different groups at CCA, launched Secret Project Taiwan, and I’m excited for the next series of “doing things that don’t scale”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continue to discover interesting businesses/products/regulations when speaking with friends who are currently living in China. It has also been interesting to see how people to react to these news when sharing them on social media. I wonder if there would be an interest in a channel dedicated to this, perhaps a newsletter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working without a boss is something that very few people on this planet has experience with. In most situations, we have a teacher, a boss, a senior of some sort, who would present a clear goal that we need to deliver on. By working on side projects, especially since being out-of-school, is my way to develop a better sense of setting goals and deadlines. I’ve always found myself working procrastinating when I can, and my current way of going around that, is to set up some sort of social obligations to make sure I will meet those ‘psuedo’ deadlines. I wonder how other people make sure they work on projects that don’t have deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a feeling that I really need to concentrate for the next few months (like when making thesis and Secret Project). I need to become much more fluent with coding and discussing/designing physical products and deliver on a few more projects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">This week, I’ve finally abandoned Apple Podcasts and switched to Breaker Podcasts. I’v had the Breaker app for a few months now but was never compelled to actually start using it. It wasn’t until a podcast I was listening to had half of their season missing on Apple Podcasts, that I decided to switch to Breaker, and I will probably never look back. Different from the Apple Podcasts, I love the fact that you can adjust playing speed and make it specific to each podcast. It’s also helpful to see how many podcasts I’ve listened to; I’ve never gotten a sense on how many podcasts I’ve completed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Time, Coding, Website | #7</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-28/weeknote-7" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time, Coding, Website | #7" /><published>2018-10-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-10-28/weeknote-7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-28/weeknote-7">&lt;p&gt;This week went by very fast. I really enjoyed working on shadowing the project at work, learning more about the technical aspect of what we are building, and brainstorming possible interfaces. That was very fun. This process definitely motivated and reminded to learn more coding sooner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have this current website running for about a month and half, I’ve been thinking more about whether I want to show my design projects online. And if I do, which ones would I want to show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending quite a bit of my free time working on portfolio and applying and interviewing, I think I now am actually available to spend my free time on learning new skills.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">This week went by very fast. I really enjoyed working on shadowing the project at work, learning more about the technical aspect of what we are building, and brainstorming possible interfaces. That was very fun. This process definitely motivated and reminded to learn more coding sooner.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unsplash, Kickstarter, Job | #6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-21/weeknote-6" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unsplash, Kickstarter, Job | #6" /><published>2018-10-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-10-21/weeknote-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-21/weeknote-6">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/bbcube.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BBCube's campaign cover photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launching a Quickstarter through Kickstarter call &amp;amp;BBCube tomorrow and I’m so nervous about it! I love it when a project is coming together and is ready to be shared. It has also been a while since I’ve worked on something purely because it’s fun. Regardless, I’m really curious about how people will receive this tabletop game; I’ve never made and publish a game before. If there’s anyone reading this, you can view the campaign &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1324099197/764280191?ref=585642&amp;amp;token=938a7210&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1538362548041-c875d78a67c5?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=62159c7c033b1da98ce840d89dae0e41&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=2544&amp;amp;q=80&quot; alt=&quot;an unsplash photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, I started uploading photos I took on a film camera (four years ago) to &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@speculatvglitch&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;, cause I figured someone might make use of the photos. And I’m now super close to reaching 2 million views on Unsplash, which is kind of crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I failed to do as much work as I wanted to. I’m hoping to get more work done this week task by task. Currenly I’m just using a long-ass bullet list to keep track of what I’m doing. It is pretty satifying to be able to scroll down and see a long list of tasks that have been completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/bbcubesticker.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BBCube's sticker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;amp;BBCube is now funded and there are about 17 days left for the campaign. I think I’m finally understanding how much work it takes to launch a crowdfunding campaign, and how much work there is ahead of us; once the campaign ends. I think one of the main lesson learned here is the amount of promotion needed for a project/campaign. When we first saw Kickstarter’s Quickstarter: an initiative to encourage indie creators to launch and test their idea, we thought that it would be perfect, because it gives us constraints such as [spend less than 3 months on it], [set your campaign goal to under $1k]. I think it’s still a great initiative as it motivated us to launch something, because it sounds much less intimidating, but it very much limits the campaign to being a very small campaign (partially because we aren’t featured by Kickstarter, and don’t know how to get featured).  Regardless, it’s still a great learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This coming week will probably be a pivoting week in retrospect. I need to make a job decision, and while I want to take on everything, I can’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very excited by what lays ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a life update I sent to someone a little while ago, I think it still very much summarizes what I’ve been thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extending thesis:&lt;/strong&gt;
For my thesis presentation, I acted out as a computer and started my presentation with “Hello, I’m a computer. I spend most of my day in your pocket… On average, you spend more than 1/3 of your day with me, and I’m not sure if you should be doign that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m thinking about studying/investigating different topics and compiling my studies into presentations that start with “Hello, I’m a house”, “Hello, I’m a city”, “Hello, I’m money”, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grad school:&lt;/strong&gt;
Like I mentioned the last time we met, I would like to go to grad school in the next 2-4 years, for something at the intersection of HCI &amp;amp; Architecture/Urban Systems. However, that doesn’t seem to exist any more (I wish The Architecture Machine Group is still a thing today.) Perhaps, the closest thing to something like this today, is Dynamicland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speculative design:&lt;/strong&gt;
Something I’ve been thinking a lot: Does one need to make sacrifice(s) by making a vision real? Recently, I’ve had several discussions about the differences between doing research or academic work versus making products that will participate in people’s everyday life. It seems like, those who prefer to do (academic) research, believe that (commercial) products cannot fully represent the vision, and those who work on products that get shipped, believe that research is conceptual and ‘fluffy’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there an in-between? Can we introduce speculative design/poetic products into people’s everyday life? Two of my friends and I have been wanting to start a hardware startup/lab, where we make small batch poetic products and introduce them to the market, not design competitions. (hopefully more on this later, we are still in the talking phase)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Indie Makers, Starting Small | #5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-14/weeknote-5" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Indie Makers, Starting Small | #5" /><published>2018-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-10-14/weeknote-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-14/weeknote-5">&lt;p&gt;Recently, my commute time has increased slightly and coincidently, I’ve stumbled upon several more podcasts to enjoy. In particular, I’ve spent quite a lot of time reading/listening (ironically not so much making yet) about indie makers and digital nomads. The discovery of this type of lifestyle / source of income has again validated the benefits of being fluent in code. At the same time, it seems that there are an increasing amount of small funds/platforms built to support indie makers. I wonder if and when there will be a group of indie makers who will focus on &lt;em&gt;physical products&lt;/em&gt;. While the internet is great and accessible (kind of), it feels like too many people’s working on the internet. I wonder what it would take to incentivize people to invest their talent into other sectors.
After listening to the stories behind serveral indie makers (sadly all male so far), I’ve learned that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All mailing lists start with having 1 subscriber&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All products start with having 1 (paying) customer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first thing you make almost never take off&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If there’s a pattern across all indie makers, it is that they are all &lt;em&gt;prolific&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is more helpful to aim small, such as acquiring just 100 paying customers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always charge more than what you think you should be charging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of starting small, and to begin exploring physical products, I will make an analog newsletter, tentatively called &amp;amp;Infrastructorial. I find it so hard to spend time on email newsletters that I want to care, and I always spend more time reading (small) physical things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wanting to do an interview series where we present technologists in a more humane way. I find it unhelpful to portray technologists as people with superpower, because in reality, they are all humans. While I keep on coming back to this interview series, I’m beginning to think that it’d be more helpful to build a community/platform around this. Perhaps it will be centered around &amp;amp;halfbaked thoughts. Quite a lot of people I know want to write weekly notes publicly, but hasn’t been consistent with it. I wonder if we can incentivize people to write week notes collectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrote a one-sentence description about &amp;amp;halfbaked: Half baked surfaces things that keep people up at night. It is a weekly mailing list where any curious human can share scribbles of what they are thinking. Will set up newsletter this week and see if there’s any interest. If anything, I like how approachable the notion of [half baked] is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I attended the Whole Earth Catalog 50th Anniversary, it has been a while since I’ve sat down for more than an hour and just listen to somebody else to speak (in the same room). I love this one slide Stewart Brand had: having access to tools and skills confers agency. The idea that a thinking space can confer agency is something that I should be thinking about more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/agency.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Whole Earth Catalog 50th Anniversary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition was very nice as well. I didn’t how prolific the group was, until seeing all of the publications laid out on both sides of a very long hallway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/50th.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Whole Earth Catalog 50th Anniversary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">Recently, my commute time has increased slightly and coincidently, I’ve stumbled upon several more podcasts to enjoy. In particular, I’ve spent quite a lot of time reading/listening (ironically not so much making yet) about indie makers and digital nomads. The discovery of this type of lifestyle / source of income has again validated the benefits of being fluent in code. At the same time, it seems that there are an increasing amount of small funds/platforms built to support indie makers. I wonder if and when there will be a group of indie makers who will focus on physical products. While the internet is great and accessible (kind of), it feels like too many people’s working on the internet. I wonder what it would take to incentivize people to invest their talent into other sectors. After listening to the stories behind serveral indie makers (sadly all male so far), I’ve learned that: All mailing lists start with having 1 subscriber All products start with having 1 (paying) customer The first thing you make almost never take off If there’s a pattern across all indie makers, it is that they are all prolific It is more helpful to aim small, such as acquiring just 100 paying customers Always charge more than what you think you should be charging</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Work, School, Reality | #4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-05/weeknote-4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work, School, Reality | #4" /><published>2018-10-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-10-05/weeknote-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-05/weeknote-4">&lt;p&gt;This week feels like a week of production work. I spent much less time thinking and a lot more time executing. It feels nice to balance the week with some making, and shipping. It also feels nice to see a project coming together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a design school, many students (including me) talk about the want to start our own (design-related) thing. Earlier in the week, I was asked if that desire comes from wanting to extend what I felt and experienced in school, because you then become a small consulting firm. Whereas, if the desire comes from wanting to build a business that can scale, then the work/commitment required is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people talk about world views. I wonder if there’s such thing as world heights. Do we think and operate at different world heights, due to what we’ve been exposed to? How are world heights different from world views?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, I gave a tour at the &amp;amp;lab to a group of foreigners. Toward the end of the tour, they mentioned that they rarely interfaced with women when they were in SF, visiting different kinds of organizations. I genuinely wish that won’t be case in the near future. Now that I have worked at a few different environments (each for a relatively short period of time), I see how problematic this is, and observe how often I feel defeated as someone who has a “softer” voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since graduation, I’ve been building physical things, and it requires significantly more work. Yet, it feels so much more satisfying to make real objects. While a good group of people are advocating for virtual and augmented reality, I wonder what it takes for the reality to revenge. In my head, I sometimes compare the world of Harry Potter to the world of Ready Player One, and the former just feels more magical to me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">This week feels like a week of production work. I spent much less time thinking and a lot more time executing. It feels nice to balance the week with some making, and shipping. It also feels nice to see a project coming together.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lost | #3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-09-28/weeknote-3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lost | #3" /><published>2018-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-09-28/weeknote-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-09-28/weeknote-3">&lt;p&gt;I feel exponentially lost.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">I feel exponentially lost.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Architecture, Cedric Price | #2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-09-21/weeknote-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Architecture, Cedric Price | #2" /><published>2018-09-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-09-21/weeknote-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-09-21/weeknote-2">&lt;p&gt;“Technology is the answer, but what was the question?” Cedric Price asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently half way through “Architectural Intelligence” by Molly Wright Steenson. Since the beginning of my senior year, I have been fascinated by the relationship between the bits and atoms, the physical and the digital, the architectural and the computational. At some point, I would love to go to (or help create) a grad school that offers something in between, instead of one or the other. I also hope that, my senior thesis on “The “Space” of Computing” is only the beginning of my investigation in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I feel that the real definition of architecture is that which through a natural distortion of time, place, and interval creates beneficial social conditions that hitherto were considered impossible.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the quote above, I find it curious that he defined architecture as a way to &lt;em&gt;distort&lt;/em&gt; time, place, and interval. To an extend, the word “distort” feels more intentional, genuine, speculative, and playful than words like “intervene”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In Price’s work the purpose of technology was “to take part in the architectural debate, perhaps through contribution, disputation, or the ability to shock.” Price used technology as a provocation for change — change in the design process, change in how people interacted with buildings and cities, change in the status quo.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, this is what (feels to me) is missing in today’s digital design. Technology has “the ability to shock” and can be used “as a provocation for change”. Digital design today does the opposite of creating “space” for people to reflect. Instead, we’ve been architecting digital “spaces” so that the paths are fixed, and predictable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/digital_is_physical.png&quot; alt=&quot;kiosk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;, (this comma separates notes from different days)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does one need to make sacrifice(s) by making a vision real? Recently, I’ve had several discussions about the difference between doing research or academic work versus making products that will participate in people’s everyday life. It seems like, those who prefer to do research, believe that (commercial) products cannot fully represent the vision, and those who work on products that are shipping, believe that research is conceptual and ‘fluffy’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there an in-between? Can we introduce speculative work into people’s everyday life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout my senior thesis, I struggled tremendously in translating what I was thinking into something others could relate to, and hence begin to care about. I asked myself, do I care if others don’t understand it? And I cared. I ended up acting out as a computer and shared that as a computer, I wish that my relationship with you will be more than what it is right now. In retrospect, if I chose not to translate my thinking/work into something that’s relatable and understandable, I would have done zero work, or at least that’s my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If a tree falls in the forest, and nobody heard it, did it make a sound?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If someone has done work, and nobody understands it, was the work done?” I’m pretty sure my answer is no.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">“Technology is the answer, but what was the question?” Cedric Price asked.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Four years, post-college, freelancing, collective | #1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-09-15/weeknote-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Four years, post-college, freelancing, collective | #1 " /><published>2018-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-09-15/weeknote-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-09-15/weeknote-1">&lt;p&gt;It has been 4 months since I’ve graduated from college, and 4 years since I’ve graduated from high school. Time flies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I graduated from high school, college graduation sounded faraway. Yet, here I am. Looking back at the past four years, I’m certain that I’ve learned a lot, about relationships, industries, personalities, interactions, and more. I’m also certain that I’ve lost a few qualities that I used to possess, perhaps in an unfortunate way. For example, I find myself becoming a little more practical and less experimental than three years ago. I hope that by being aware of this, I will find myself being more wild than I currently am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, in college, I was being cautioned that I should care more about those around me. I think I now am better at identifying when I should care more, but still need to be more proactive in caring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since returning from summer travels, I’ve taken on a few contracting positions. Freelancing right out of school in some way forces myself to pick up a few skills quickly, because I’m not shielded by a consultancy. Being challenged feels great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;amp;OhDotZero recently finished our first project; two kiosks for the Global Climate Action Summit. At the kiosk, you can pick your miniature home appliances and place them onto the floor plan to see how much energy and water you use. To make the numbers more relatable, we converted kwh and gallons of water into number of iphone charges and bottles of water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/kiosk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kiosk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the two kiosks look cute and well put-together. I personally also learned a lot about where I fall short and strive when it comes to collaborating and delegating. Additionally, it also made me realize (once again) just how much more I need to learn; both soft and hard skills wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;amp;Lab got paused for a little bit because of the recent &amp;amp;OhDotZero project. Self-starting something, even with friends, is hard. There are no formal deadlines, which makes everything too flexible. Sometimes, I wish there’s a school that would let you graduate only if your collective/business is self-sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/calendar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kiosk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since senior year, I’ve been taping a four-month calendar to the top of my laptop, to keep track of deadlines and to-dos. It helped me tremendously in acknowledging and acting on the to-dos for my thesis. However, this calendar hasn’t been as effective now. Perhaps because my to-dos are all listed on the page, instead of associated with a date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I’ve always remembered from my dad is that, life isn’t fair, the only thing that’s fair is that everyone has 24 hours. And perhaps that’s why &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=62CUg45lMtQ&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; Devinsupertramps’ video resonates with me so much.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">It has been 4 months since I’ve graduated from college, and 4 years since I’ve graduated from high school. Time flies.</summary></entry></feed>