<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-20T12:35:02-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Weiwei Hsu</title><subtitle>be courageous</subtitle><author><name>Weiwei</name><email>wei@weiweihsu.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Becoming Courageous, Together</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-02-20/becoming-courageous-together" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Becoming Courageous, Together" /><published>2019-02-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-02-20/becoming-courageous-together</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-02-20/becoming-courageous-together">&lt;p&gt;This post is a post-mortem of a 7-day summer-camp/workshop I ran during the summer of freshman and sophomore year, called Secret Project Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever people ask me which project I’m the proudest of, I have never hesitated in saying: “It’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170628055307/https://www.cca.edu/news/2015/11/24/student-takes-secret-project-abroad&quot;&gt;Secret Project Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;, a summer-camp-like thing I did four years ago”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past four years, I never really wrote about what the project was, and why it was a meaningful project to me, and to others. For some reason, I’ve been thinking about this project a lot lately, so I decided to write about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sptw-360-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A static 360 photo of Secret Project Taiwan 2016&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A 360˚ photo of SPTW 2016&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;secret-project-taiwan&quot;&gt;Secret Project Taiwan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout college, one of the most life-changing programs for me was called Secret Project at CCA, directed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Bielenberg&quot;&gt;John Bielenberg&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://marcobrien.net&quot;&gt;Marc O’Brien&lt;/a&gt;. The program encouraged everyone to think wrong and to challenge the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was through Secret Project Blitzes (which were weekend workshops and spring break trips), I realized how powerful it is to dream, and to imagine, together with others:
We towed an airstream from California to Nevada to Utah and back. We got to collaborate with students from all majors, at all levels. We worked with several non-profits to brainstorm new products, marketing channels, etc. We dreamed of buying a container ship and sailing around the world (which, someone is doing a version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/100&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having gone through public and private schools in China, Secret Project was the opposite of “listen to your teachers, do your homework, maybe be just a little creative” culture I was used to. Participating in the Secret Project gave me ideas to run a version of it in Taiwan, where my parents are from. During the summer of 2015 and 2016, I produced and co-facilitated a 7-day workshop known as Secret Project Taiwan (SPTW), during which ~15 college students came together to think of wild ideas, make small bets, and test them out together, on a 500-acre large farm south-east of Taipei. Everyone signed up for this summer camp with the intention to practice brainstorming and pitching ideas, but it ended up being much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sptw-farm.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Day 1 of Secret Project Taiwan 2016&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Day 1 of Secret Project Taiwan 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-used-to-trying-new-things&quot;&gt;Getting used to trying new things&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different from a typical college summer camp in Taiwan, SPTW was unique in a few different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It was an English-speaking camp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All of us were studying in 4+ different cities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People came from 8+ different majors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It was a summer camp ran by college students, for college students (the session in 2015 was facilitated by Marc O’Brien, a CCA professor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, SPTW was a hotbed for experiments and weird and wild ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, my co-facilitators Will, Bill, and I did put some loose structure in place. Below is a screenshot of the schedule we created. While it may look intimidating, they were all fun (and occasionally nerve-wracking) activities. For example, Be Bold was a session dedicated to “moonshot ideas”, Let Go was a session on “parking” our earlier ideas to come up with new ones, Small Bets was a session on creating MVPs. These are all activities part of the Think Wrong exercise, which you can learn more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=srq7BBemFY4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also added our own flavor to the week. We introduced PechaKucha to everyone, and we all had to pitch each other our ideas with 10 slides that would each last 10 seconds. We all learned to dance to Mark Ronson and Bruno Mars’ Uptown Funk. We wrote a contract that said “I will leave humanity better then I found it,” and everyone signed it. We introduced Storytime for people to share a weird project or story with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sptw-schedule.png&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of SPTW's schedule&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A screenshot of SPTW’s schedule&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;show-me-your-guts&quot;&gt;Show Me Your Guts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tradition of Secret Project and its precursor &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projectmlab.com&quot;&gt;Project M&lt;/a&gt; was something called Show Me Your Guts, and I would like to highlight it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this event is that everyone would have 24 hours to prepare for it, and during Show Me Your Guts, we would all gather around the bonfire, and either share something we’ve never said out loud before, or do something we’ve never done in front of others, no exceptions. We had a bottle of whiskey, and whenever someone’s ready to show their guts, they would start their story with having one whisk of whiskey. Until they take another whisk, nobody could interrupt them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By being vulnerable in front of each other,&lt;/strong&gt; Show Me Your Guts brought all of us together in a unique way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were no longer complete strangers to each other. Instead, we each became extremely supportive, caring, and bold with what and how we brainstorm, collaborate, and make for the remaining time we had together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/guts.png&quot; alt=&quot;Show Me Your Guts from Secret Project Taiwan 2015&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Show Me Your Guts from SPTW 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;missing-ingredients&quot;&gt;Missing ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the 7-day workshop, everyone all got a taste of what it’s like to be bold, to collaborate, and be extremely experimental. To an extent, the workshop helped everyone to become a little more courageous, by trying new things together. However, upon leaving the SPTW and returning to each of their own lives, everyone felt that their everyday life was business-as-usual again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One common feedback we received from participants, was that they all wished SPTW was a year-long gap year program, instead of a week-long “summer camp.” Over the past few years, I have been thinking about what it’d be like to run a more extended version of Secret Project Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is it for?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would be an ideal outcome?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would everyone do every day for a few months, or for a year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having graduated from college a few months ago, I’ve also been exploring what I want to devote my time to, and how I can do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What kind of environment do I wish to be in?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What kind of people do I wish to surround myself with?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What should I devote my career to?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much autonomy do I want in the work I do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never ran another SPTW since my sophomore year, because I had to get a design internship in my junior year to graduate, and I’ve been working since I’ve graduated. Lately, memories from SPTW have been coming back to me, and I can’t shake the above questions off my mind. Maybe it is time for a longer version of this camp, for us all to become more courageous, together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very much looking forward to what might come out of this exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sptw-ninja.png&quot; alt=&quot;All participants and co-facilitators from Secret Project Taiwan&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;All participants and co-facilitators from Secret Project Taiwan 2015 and 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you Christina Liu, Tomo Kihara, and William Felker for giving thoughtful feedback and comments.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Extra special thanks to my parents, John Bielenberg, Marc O’Brien, Christina Liu, Bill Chien, and Damon Lam for being supportive of this project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">This post is a post-mortem of a 7-day summer-camp/workshop I ran during the summer of freshman and sophomore year, called Secret Project Taiwan.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Slow and steady, Adoption | #20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-02-17/weeknotes-20" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=" Slow and steady, Adoption | #20" /><published>2019-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-02-17/weeknotes-20</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-02-17/weeknotes-20">&lt;p&gt;This is my 20th weeknotes. It feels like I’ve been writing weeknotes for half a year now but I suppose I’m still a few weeks short from that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week went by really fast. I don’t feel like much happened, yet my calendar was pretty full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels like I’m getting closer to doing what I’d like to do in the next phase of life. Website’s almost done thanks to teammate, got a few positive and interesting feedback from friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed a brief discussion about ‘killer app’ at work. If one were to invent a medium for humanity to communicate with and think with, it is important to ask questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why and how would the society adopt this medium?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we get buy-ins from people, or what is the ‘killer app’?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To an extent, the public library or books as a medium had a ‘killer app’ called the bible, disposable paper in general had a ‘killer app’ where it enabled people to communiate with each other through mail and postal services.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">This is my 20th weeknotes. It feels like I’ve been writing weeknotes for half a year now but I suppose I’m still a few weeks short from that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Events, Catching up, Like-minded people | #19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-02-10/weeknotes-19" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Events, Catching up, Like-minded people | #19" /><published>2019-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-02-10/weeknotes-19</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-02-10/weeknotes-19">&lt;p&gt;Missed a week of weeknotes, so here’s a long one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These past two weeks were a lot of absorbing and digesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended the first social systems game night in San Francisco, it was very fun to play games with people who have similar interests. Since there were ~30 people, we were divided into smaller groups, and it was fascinating to hear every group’s game results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also attended the first Micromobility Conference, out of curiousity, and personal interest in urban systems. It was very refreshing to be with a large group of people that aren’t primarily there to discuss design or engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, both of these events made me want to attend more first-of-its-kind event/conference more in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These past two weeks were also full of meeting new people and catching up with old friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had dinner with some of my college friends. It’s fun to go down a memory-viewing-mode and discuss some of the things that happened in college. I always find it nice to meet up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Met with a few groups that work for non-profit, animation company, and independent researchers. It is so refreshing and delightful to meet new people that share similar interests and goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addtionally, I’m very greatful to those who offered their time to share advice, skills, and tips. Some of the conversations helped me understand that I may be better suited for operational work (with some design work invovled), some of the conversations helped me understand the possible products/services that an individual or a small team of 2-3 can build; beyond sass and physical products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s surprising to reunite with someone that I met a few years ago for a workshop, and realizing that we’ve been thinking about similar things for the past few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also is quite magical to find or start a tribe where people are all at similar career phase, and all share similar and weird goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a friend, I’ve learned quite a bit about European design culture over the past few days. It was great to learn that many design/technology people are funded by governmental grants, and that provides a completely different incentive structure for people to think and plan for their career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m now at a point where I cannot stop thinking about a model that can help people to gain creative autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">Missed a week of weeknotes, so here’s a long one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Collective creative freedom | #18</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-27/weeknotes-18" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Collective creative freedom | #18" /><published>2019-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-27/weeknotes-18</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-27/weeknotes-18">&lt;p&gt;In my weeknotes &lt;a href=&quot;http://weiweihsu.com/2018-11-10/weeknote-9&quot;&gt;#9&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote about the idea creative freedom:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This idea of gaining creative freedom, or research freedom, is perhaps something that I find many different communities strive for (the new indie vc movement, digital nomads, patreon creators, kickstarter creators, indie hackers, to name a few.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The question I’ve been thinking about this week, in relation to creative freedom, is whether there should be a school that helps you to gain creative freedom. Job security is no longer the only goal people have for their careers. However, it is still very hard for people to wrap their head around, and be brave enough to get started with gaining creative freedom (especially those who live in an environment that culturally encourages to climb the corporate ladder, or stick with a ‘safe job’.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I believe that Secret Project Taiwan was a step toward that direction, but currently I don’t know how I could be taking it another step furthur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 months later, I think I now have a better sense of how to begin to own creative freedom, collectively. Hopefully, I will have more to share soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite a lot of things happened this week..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since graduation, I have been thinking a lot about what I would like to work on, and how I can get there. A few months have gone by now, and I think I’ve realized that I need a balance between exploring and experimenting with tools creation, but at the same time, making it available and accessible to others. At the same time, I’ve been searching for places where I can explore the intersection of computing and architecture/urbanism. I think I have found a group of people that does precisely these, and it feels like discovering earthlings when you think you are the only one residing on Mars..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a publication date for the first paper that I’ve co-authored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to school to pick up my student excellence in leadership awards, and reading about why I was nominated and awarded with the awards feels like getting a flashback of everything that happened during college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most importantly, I feel a lot clearer about what I want to do and how I can get there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">In my weeknotes #9, I wrote about the idea creative freedom:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Break, Home, Back | #17</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-13/weeknotes-17" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Break, Home, Back | #17" /><published>2019-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-13/weeknotes-17</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-13/weeknotes-17">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a month since I last synced weeknotes to the website. I tried out writing weeknotes in Apple Notes for the last month and I think I still prefer writing it in Atom and pushing it to the world of connected bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a wonderful break. I was able to spend a ton of time at home, catch up with friends that I get to see once every 2-4 years, and reflect on the past few months as well as the past 4 four years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some feelings:
It’s weird to be back and see how the place I grew up in feels unfamiliar because of how technology is now weaved into the city. It’s exciting to see how people that I’ve crossed paths with before are all working toward their own goals. It’s motivating to see how companies here work, collaborate, and experiment to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
I’m now at the airport. It’s been a while since I last spent this many weeks at home. And when home finally feels normal again, it’s time to leave. It feels weird to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having taken a break, where I was able to truly get bored, it’s time to get serious this year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">It’s been a month since I last synced weeknotes to the website. I tried out writing weeknotes in Apple Notes for the last month and I think I still prefer writing it in Atom and pushing it to the world of connected bits.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book, Communication | #16</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-06/weeknotes-16" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book, Communication | #16" /><published>2019-01-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-06/weeknotes-16</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-06/weeknotes-16">&lt;p&gt;Spent the first day of 2019 finishing Kaifu Lee’s “AI Superpower”. It’s been a while since I’ve started and finished a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to read the book in Chinese because I’ve realized that it’s hard for me to have a conversation about anything technology related in Chinese, that’s because I learned to talk about design and technology in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned quite a bit from reading the book, and seeing how he positioned the book in different countries. The book also showed me a way to explain some of the dangers and solutions to those who think technology has near-zero negative impact.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">Spent the first day of 2019 finishing Kaifu Lee’s “AI Superpower”. It’s been a while since I’ve started and finished a book.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Things in 2018 | #15</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-30/weeknotes-15" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Things in 2018 | #15" /><published>2018-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-30/weeknotes-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-30/weeknotes-15">&lt;p&gt;I wanted to document everything I’ve done and have not done this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why I’ve decided to do this is because I’ve graduate from college, and life/what I’ve done is entirely up to me (although that is true to school too.) This will probably be the 10000th times you’ve seen someone doing this, but this will be the first time for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got very sick in January because of over-working in the previous semester&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got to invite the designer I respect the most to speak at CCA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got to meet someone I first met on Twitter in person&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I promised myself to not slack off on thesis and I didn’t&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduated from CCA with distinction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Co-won a grant to work on a housing project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got the highest grade for thesis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thesis zine was exhibited in New York&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrote a paper with my favorite teacher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talked to an English-speaking energy worker for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Traveled to New York for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Took on multiple contract work at once&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explored and researched different business models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launched and shipped a Kickstarter project for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had my first holiday break as an ‘adult’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reunited with more than half of my high school classmates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learned to do basic modeling in Rhino&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coded my website&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made an analog version of my portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visited a Chinese Tech company&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started reading books in Chinese again&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confronted the reality of fighting for creative and research freedom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overall, I was very confused with what I want to do, how I could fit in in the design world, and if I should try and fit in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–
It is now one hour away from 2019. Unlike some people, I don’t feel like 2018 is a year that I cannot top, but it also wasn’t a bad year. I feel like, one bad habit I got rid of this year was how lazy I get after thinking through how a project can play out (I used to think that if a project can happen, then I don’t really need to realize it..)
One thing I aiming to get better at next year, is to execute a ton more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">I wanted to document everything I’ve done and have not done this year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Custom orders| #14</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-23/weeknotes-14" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Custom orders| #14" /><published>2018-12-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-23/weeknotes-14</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-23/weeknotes-14">&lt;p&gt;This time back, I’ve been ordering customized prints and cards for friend’s companies and myself. That process (not really an experience) is an entirely different one than in America. In America, most people have built a website that covers the entire process so that they don’t have to interface with you. Here in China, you would view their store to get the gist of what you would receive, but the negotiation and file-checking etc are all through a chat. I gotta say, I prefer the latter, even though there are rarely any pretty visual design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a version of the custom brass stamp I’m ordering. You can switch out the characters because there’s a removable stopper that’s magnetically attached to the stamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/letter stamp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;custom-made stamp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">This time back, I’ve been ordering customized prints and cards for friend’s companies and myself. That process (not really an experience) is an entirely different one than in America. In America, most people have built a website that covers the entire process so that they don’t have to interface with you. Here in China, you would view their store to get the gist of what you would receive, but the negotiation and file-checking etc are all through a chat. I gotta say, I prefer the latter, even though there are rarely any pretty visual design.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Payment systems, Alternative business models| #13</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-16/weeknotes-13" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Payment systems, Alternative business models| #13" /><published>2018-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-16/weeknotes-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-16/weeknotes-13">&lt;p&gt;Skipped a week of weeknotes because I was traveling and getting distracted by being home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I’m using Alipay and WeChat Pay and it’s so fascinating to participate in this ecosystem. There hasn’t been a store/place that doesn’t accept one of those payment. In fact, most places don’t accept credit cards and only accept Alipay or WeChat Pay (this is due to the face that shops need to pay a deposit to rent the device to accept payment, and accepting multiple forms of payments means paying for lots of deposit $$$)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a version of Square in China, the main difference here is that there’s a camera for scanning QR code. Another difference is that, every store I’ve been to almost always has a different payment machine/device, probably because each comes with different features and are sold at a different price point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/paymentsh.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;payment device in Shanghai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently watched Connie Chan’s video on &lt;a href=&quot;https://weiweihsu.typeform.com/to/PuycXI&quot;&gt;alternative business models in China&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s pretty inspiring to see all of those business models all-at-once. In America, and most of the world, there exist three different models: subscription-based, ad-based (hence attention-based), and/or a mix of both. In China, there are ebook apps where you only need to pay to unlock the ending, or you pay by the # of characters you read, there are streaming services where you pay only after watching the first five minutes of the movie, or you pay by tipping the authors/creators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great motivation for pursuing alternative business models when creating digital and analog products.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">Skipped a week of weeknotes because I was traveling and getting distracted by being home.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflection | #12</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-01/weeknote-12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflection | #12" /><published>2018-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-01/weeknote-12</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-12-01/weeknote-12">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve been looking back at the think wrong chart, and thinking about how I’m falling into the trap of going for the safe route. To be honest, ever since graduation, societal pressure around getting a job has been pulling me away from all the ambitions I had when I was in freshman and sophomore year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have learned a lot in the past few months, especially around the importance of aligning goals, and how to frame a proposal. I think it is fair to say that I’m now more motivated to work on what I believe in.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Weiwei Hsu</name></author><summary type="html">Recently, I’ve been looking back at the think wrong chart, and thinking about how I’m falling into the trap of going for the safe route. To be honest, ever since graduation, societal pressure around getting a job has been pulling me away from all the ambitions I had when I was in freshman and sophomore year.</summary></entry></feed>